Privacy Policy
==============

**Effective Date: March 22, 2024**

This Privacy Policy applies to personal and other information that may be collected when you interact with the Barnes & Noble enterprise, which consists of (a) Barnes & Noble, Inc., its subsidiaries and any brands owned by Barnes & Noble, including: B. Dalton Bookseller, Bookstar, Boxer Books, Em and Friends, Knock Knock, NOOK, Paper Source, Sparknotes, Tattered Cover, Union Square & Co., and Who’s There, as well as their respective businesses and operations (collectively, “Barnes & Noble”); (b) businesses and operations managed or operated by Barnes & Noble; (c) websites owned, operated and managed by Barnes & Noble, including each website that links to this Privacy Policy, (collectively, “Barnes & Noble Websites”); and (d) Barnes & Noble and NOOK devices (“Devices”), content, software and mobile applications (“Apps”).

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Barnes & Noble, and we believe that a single, comprehensive privacy policy that is straightforward and clear is in the best interests of our customers and our businesses.

Personal information is sometimes referred to as personal data in certain jurisdictions.

To review the prior version of Barnes & Noble’s Privacy Policy, please [click here](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/privacy-policy-previous).

Barnes & Noble reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time. You will be notified of any material changes to this Privacy Policy which are less protective of customer information prior to such changes becoming effective. We may notify you of these changes by email reminders, by notice on this site, or by other acceptable means. Such modifications will only apply to information collected on, or after, the date of the modification.

While this Privacy Policy provides you with information about our privacy practices and certain rights, our [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/about/terms-of-use) governs our relationship with you, including your transactions with us and your use of Barnes & Noble Websites and visits to our Stores.

Below you will find answers to the following frequently asked questions and information about how we collect, use and share your personal information:

[HOW DO WE RESPECT YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?](#section8)  
[BARNES & NOBLE DOES NOT SELL OR SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.](#section9)  
[ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES: U.S. STATE PRIVACY NOTICE & CALIFORNIA NOTICE AT COLLECTION](#section11)  
[ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES FOR VISITORS OUTSIDE THE U.S., INCLUDING IN THE EU, UK & SWITZERLAND, AND INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS](#section12)  
[WHOM DO I CONTACT AT BARNES & NOBLE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS?](#section14)

WHAT IS THE PERSONAL INFORMATION THAT WE COLLECT?
-------------------------------------------------

Depending on how you choose to interact with Barnes & Noble, we may collect personal information from you, for example your name, email address, billing address, shipping address, phone number, credit card or bank account information, day and month of birth and other persistent identifiers that can be used to personally identify you. We may also collect other personal information regarding your interaction with Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices and Apps, including usage information, the items that you browse, purchase, download, read, watch and otherwise access, and your geographic location, and your communications with Barnes & Noble.

WHY DO WE COLLECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?
---------------------------------------

We collect your personal information in an effort to provide you with a superior customer experience and, as necessary, to administer our business. It allows us to provide you with easy access to our products and services, with a particular focus on the items and programs that may be of most interest to you. For more information as to why we collect personal information, please see the section below entitled **How do we use your personal information?**

Your personal information also allows us to communicate with you about special offers, promotions, and other marketing programs and news that may be of interest to you. You always have the opportunity to unsubscribe from promotional emails by following the instructions included in each marketing email or by changing your preferences in your account. You may unsubscribe from mobile notifications by changing your settings in the Apps or on your Barnes & Noble or third-party device.

HOW DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
--------------------------------------------

### Information that you provide to us

As a general matter, you can browse in our stores and on the Barnes & Noble Websites without submitting your personal information to us, although we may receive and collect certain personal information automatically, as outlined in the section entitled **Information Automatically Collected** of this Privacy Policy, including site analytics regarding our websites, information your Internet browser automatically sends when you visit our websites, and information collected by cookies.

However, there are a number of circumstances in which you may need to provide us with your personal information. The most common of these circumstances include:

* Making a purchase or placing an order
* Creating an account or joining Barnes & Noble Member Programs
* Enrolling in Em & Friends — Friends with Benefits
* Enrolling in the Paper Source Marketing Program
* Applying for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard
* Using Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices and Apps
* Contacting customer service
* Entering a sweepstakes or contest
* Interacting with social media sites
* Publishing through B&N Press
* Signing up for promotional communications

For your convenience, we have provided a summary description of each of these circumstances below:

### Making a purchase or placing an order

When you make a purchase or place an order in our stores, place an order online or purchase, download, rent or stream digital books, periodicals, and other digital content (“Digital Content”), you may need to submit personal information to us.

### Creating an account or joining Barnes & Noble Member Programs

In order to use Devices, certain Apps and features of Barnes & Noble Websites, or to purchase or access Digital Content, you may be required to create a password-protected user account and provide us with personal information when you do so. Similarly, when you enroll in our Barnes & Noble Premium Membership Program, Barnes & Noble Rewards, Em & Friends — Friends with Benefits, or Paper Source Marketing Program, we will ask you to submit personal information as part of your member profile. We will store and use this information to administer the programs and services in which you choose to participate, and as permitted by this Privacy Policy.

### Applying for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard

When you apply for a Barnes & Noble MasterCard, you will need to submit personal information directly to the issuer of the MasterCard. Personal information that you provide directly to the issuer is subject to the bank’s privacy policies, practices and procedures, not Barnes & Noble’s.

In addition, we disclose certain personal information to the issuer of the MasterCard in connection with the administration of the Barnes & Noble MasterCard program. The issuer does not have the right to use the personal information we provide beyond what is necessary to assist us or to administer this program. The issuer is contractually obliged to maintain the confidentiality and security of the personal information we provide and is restricted from using such information in any way not expressly authorized by us.

### Using Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices and Apps

Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices, and Apps may provide you with the ability to enter (either directly, or by authorizing Barnes & Noble to access the information from a third party such as a social networking site or application) certain information such as your contacts, calendar entries or photos, or images you may submit to us to help us locate products for you.

### Contacting Customer Service

When you contact customer service, we may ask you to provide, or confirm, personal information so that we can better serve you.

### Entering a sweepstakes or contest

If you enter a sweepstakes or contest we offer, we may ask you to provide personal information so that we can consider your entry and, if you win, so that you may redeem your prize.

### Interacting with social media sites

Our Devices and Apps may provide you with the ability to enter (directly, or by authorizing us to download the information from a third party such as a social media site or application) personal information such as contacts or lists of friends. These or related applications may also allow you to provide information directly to social media sites including information about your purchases, physical location, or comments.

### Publishing through B&N Press

If you elect to publish your content via our B&N Press service, we may ask you to provide your bank account and routing information so that we can direct payments to you.

### Signing up for promotional communications

If you sign up to receive promotional communications or notifications from us, we may ask you to provide personal information so that we can provide these to you.

### Information automatically collected

There are circumstances in which we automatically receive and collect information from you. The most common sources of this information include:

* Web server logs
* Cookies
* Pixel tags or clear GIFs
* Third party web analytics services
* Targeted advertising
* Your Device or Apps you use
* Geolocation, including general and precise location information
* Wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble in retail stores
* Social media sites
* Business partners, contractors, and other third parties

For your convenience, we have provided a summary description of each of these circumstances below:

### Web server logs

When you visit a Barnes & Noble Website, our web servers may automatically log information that your browser sends us. For example, we may receive and collect: the name of the domain and host from which you access the Internet; the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you are using; the date and time you access the Barnes & Noble Website; and the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to the Barnes & Noble Website. We may also collect information regarding search queries run on the Barnes & Noble Website. We use this information to monitor the usage of the Barnes & Noble Websites and as necessary for our business.

### Cookies

Like many online retailers, we and/or our third-party providers use cookies to recognize you as you use or return to the Barnes & Noble Websites. This is done so that we can personalize and enhance your browsing and shopping experience. “Cookies” are small files that are placed in your browser to collect information about your activities on a Barnes & Noble Website. Cookies help us to: (1) speed navigation, keep track of items in your shopping bag and provide you with content that is tailored to you; (2) remember information you gave us so that you do not have to re-enter it; (3) determine the effectiveness of some of our marketing efforts and communications; and (4) monitor the total number of visitors, pages viewed, and the total number of ads displayed.

Browsers are typically set to create cookies automatically. You can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies entirely. To learn more about the types of cookies that we use and how to manage your cookie settings please click here to access our [Cookie Policy](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/cookie-policy).

### Pixel tags or clear GIFs

We may use sensing technologies that use pixel tags or clear GIFs (which are also called web beacons). These technologies allow us to determine the effectiveness of our email and advertising and marketing efforts. For this purpose, we tie the pixel tags and clear GIFs to personally identifiable information. We may also collect information regarding the links within such marketing materials that you click on and purchase statistics regarding items you buy following receipt of such marketing.

### Third party web analytics services

We work with third party service providers, including but not limited to Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, and Localytics to help us better understand how you use the Barnes & Noble Websites. These third party service providers will place cookies in your browser to collect information such as how you were referred to the Barnes & Noble Websites, how you navigate around the Barnes & Noble Websites, what you purchase and what traffic is driven by various marketing methods. This information will help us to better serve you and provide you with more personalized information and product offerings. We do not allow third party service providers to collect your credit card information, email address, or password information. These third-party service providers may only use your personal information to perform services for us and may not share your personal information with anyone else, or use it for any other purpose, except on an aggregated, non-personally identifiable basis.

To learn more about the privacy practices of Adobe, you may review their privacy policy located [here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy.html). To exercise your choice with respect to their collection of information on Barnes & Noble Websites, please [click here](https://www.adobe.com/privacy/opt-out.html).

To learn more about the privacy practices of Google, you may review its privacy policy located [here](https://policies.google.com/privacy). To disable the Google Analytics cookie and other third-party web analytics service provider cookies, you can choose to have your browser notify you when cookies are being written to your computer or accessed, or you can disable cookies entirely.

### Targeted advertising

We may partner with third party advertising networks that collect IP addresses, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), browser type, operating system, time zone, country, referring pages, and other information through the use of cookies, web server logs and pixel tags on Barnes & Noble Websites, Apps, emails and on third party websites and emails. They use this information to provide you with advertisements that are customized to your particular preferences, including for companies that are not affiliated with us. You may see these advertisements on Barnes & Noble Websites and third party apps and websites, and across different devices you use. Barnes & Noble does not control these third party cookies. We may use this process to help us manage and improve the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. Some of our advertising partners also enable us to translate your email address or phone number into an identifier that can’t be used to identify you personally. Our advertising partners then use that unique identifier to show ads that are more relevant to you across the web and in mobile apps. If you would like to learn more about the third party advertisers that may be aware of the fact that you visit Barnes & Noble Websites or use our Apps, and to understand your opt-out choices, please visit the website of the National Advertising Initiative here or Digital Advertising Alliance, by visiting [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://www.aboutads.info/).

Some of the activities described in this section may constitute “targeted advertising,” “sharing,” or “selling” under certain laws. Depending on where you reside, you may, have the right to opt out of targeted advertising, sharing, and sales of your personal information. You may opt out of cookie-based targeted advertising and sharing by visiting the Barnes & Noble Privacy Preference Center and opting out of “Targeting Cookies.” You may opt-out of non-cookie based targeted advertising, sharing, and sales by visiting our Data Rights Request portal and selecting “Do Not Sell my data to third parties”, located here. Please note that these actions do not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads. To learn more about the choices available to you with respect to these practices, see below **How Do I Exercise My Privacy Rights and Choices?**

### Your Device or Apps you use

When you use a Device or our Apps, we automatically collect information through the Device or App when it is connected to the Internet. For example, we may receive and collect information concerning device registration, operating system, settings, usage, firmware version, signal strength, search queries, network interaction, the name of the network from which you access the Internet, the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the device you are using, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), downloads, sideloaded content, configuration, or service information relating to any malfunction of the Device or App. This may include information regarding your activity on such Devices or Apps, such as books opened, date and time of use, time elapsed, page turns, bookmarks, annotations, or customer reviews.

### Geolocation

In addition, to providing location-based services on Devices or through Apps, Barnes & Noble and third party application providers may automatically collect real-time geographic location information or other location-based information about you and your Device or other mobile device on which the App is installed. This information may be used to provide certain device or application functionality or to offer, provide and improve products and services (e.g. proximity to local Barnes & Noble Stores).

### Wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble in retail stores

When you connect your computer or mobile device to wireless networks operated by Barnes & Noble at store locations, we may collect information concerning your location, unique device identifiers (UDIDs), date and time of access and information regarding your interaction with the Barnes & Noble enterprise through Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices or Apps as permitted by this Privacy Policy. Location-based information may also help us learn how you experience our stores, to improve your store visit and, in some circumstances, deliver push notifications and other content to your Device when you are near, enter, and move through our stores. Most mobile devices will allow you to turn off location-based services.

### Social media

We may provide you the ability to sign into a Barnes & Noble Website or App using a social media account such as a Facebook, Twitter, Instagram, Snapchat, or Google account, or use your social media accounts to share information from Barnes & Noble Websites, Devices or Apps. In these cases, as well as when you use a Barnes & Noble app on a social media site or choose to join (or “like”) a Barnes & Noble page on a social media site, the social media site may provide us with certain information about you, including but not limited to your contacts and other “likes”. In addition, we may share your information, including personal information, with third party vendors to facilitate your choice to sign into a Barnes & Noble Website or App using a social media account. Please see the privacy policy for the applicable social media site to learn more about how these sites use and share your personal information.

### Business partners, contractors, and other third parties

We may collect personal information and other information about you from business partners, contractors and other third parties. This includes, but is not limited to, instances in which you affirmatively authorize third parties to provide us with information. Such information may be collected via, but not limited to, software applications that you download or use on your Device or that otherwise allow you to interact with the Barnes & Noble enterprise.

HOW DO WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION?
-----------------------------------

Barnes & Noble uses your personal information across our enterprise to provide you with a superior customer experience and, as necessary, to administer our businesses. For example, we use your personal information to:

* Provide you with products, services and information across the Barnes & Noble enterprise, including product and subject recommendations and other information in Barnes & Noble retail stores, through emails from our businesses, and on the Barnes & Noble Websites and online interactive communities, your Devices, Digital Content, Apps and software, and display associated content and advertising;
* Administer our programs;
* To protect against deceptive and fraudulent activity;
* Provide customer service in stores, by telephone and online;
* Conduct research and perform analysis in order to measure, maintain, protect, develop and improve our products and services;
* Administer sweepstakes, contests, promotions or surveys and provide appropriate notifications;
* Communicate with you about special offers, events, or new products or services that may be of interest to you;
* Customize and enhance the Barnes & Noble Websites and advertising;
* Make communications necessary to notify you regarding security, privacy, and administrative issues; and
* Manage our business.

WITH WHOM DO WE SHARE PERSONAL INFORMATION?
-------------------------------------------

Protecting the privacy and security of your personal information is a priority at Barnes & Noble. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, Barnes & Noble will not provide your personal information to third parties without your consent. Barnes & Noble shares your personal information with:

* **Other entities within the Barnes & Noble enterprise.** Barnes & Noble owns and operates other operations and businesses and we may share your personal information with our other business units and operations, even if such business units or operations are sold.
* **Service providers, subcontractors and agents who perform services on our behalf.** We provide personal information to third party service providers, subcontractors, and agents that work under contract on our behalf to provide certain services. These include third party service providers who help facilitate any communications you may have with Barnes & Noble on its website—those communications may be recorded and shared with these third parties to assist Barnes & Noble in providing this service. These third parties do not have the right to use personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by Barnes & Noble. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information.
* **Providers of products and services.** These are third parties that provide products and services you may purchase or request from or through us. These providers of products or services do not have the right to use personal information we provide to them in any way that is not authorized by Barnes & Noble. They are contractually obligated to use such information only as necessary to assist us and to maintain the confidentiality and security of such information.
* **Credit card companies.** Credit card transactions are handled by third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors who receive credit card numbers and other personal information from us to verify the credit card numbers and process transactions. Although Barnes & Noble’s treatment of this information is governed by this policy, the use of your information by the third party financial institutions and their vendors and contractors will be subject to their own privacy policies.
* **Law enforcement officials and as required by law.** Barnes & Noble may release personal information to third parties when we determine, in our judgment, and without your consent, that it is necessary to (a) comply with the law, regulation, legal process, or enforceable governmental request, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; (b) enforce or apply the terms of any of our policies or user agreements; (c) establish or exercise our rights, to defend against a legal claim, to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding possible illegal activities, suspected fraud, safety of person or property, or a violation of our policies, (d) protect the rights, property or safety of Barnes & Noble, our employees, our customers, users, or others; or (e) to comply with your request for the shipment of products to or the provision of services by a third party intermediary.
* **Co-branded offerings.** In some instances, we may offer a service or feature that is co-branded by Barnes & Noble and a third party company. If you provide information in connection with such co-branded service or feature, that information may be shared between Barnes & Noble and the third party. Although Barnes & Noble’s treatment of the information is governed by this policy, the third party’s treatment of your information will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy.
* **Other websites operated by Barnes & Noble.** In some instances, we may operate a Barnes & Noble Website on behalf of a third party. If you provide information in connection with a Barnes & Noble Website operated by Barnes & Noble on behalf of a third party, that information may be shared between Barnes & Noble and the third party. Although Barnes & Noble’s treatment of the information is governed by this policy, the third party’s treatment of your information will be subject to the third party’s privacy policy.
* **Certain Digital Content providers.** In certain cases, we may be required to forward your name, email address, IP address, and shipping or billing address to certain content providers in connection with your order. The content providers may share this information with the applicable publisher and circulation auditors, and may use this information to fulfill your order and for other purposes. In these cases, the terms of the privacy policy of the publishers whose content you have purchased or downloaded will apply to you. If you do not wish to receive marketing communications from these publishers, you must contact the publisher directly.
* **Sales, mergers, and acquisitions.** If Barnes & Noble becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, restructuring, reorganization, or any form of sale or other disposition of some or all of its assets, personal information and your transaction history may be provided to the entities and advisors involved subject to a confidentiality agreement, and we will provide notice to you at your email address on file before any personal information is finally transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. Such a transaction may involve us (i) retaining the right to continue to use transferred personal information in addition to the right of the transferee to use such information, and (ii) engaging in additional transfers of personal information (including new personal information) with the transferee from time to time following such a transaction.
* **Your Consent.** We may ask if you would like us to share your information with other unaffiliated third parties who are not described elsewhere in this policy.

HOW DO WE PROTECT PERSONAL INFORMATION?
---------------------------------------

No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is fully secure. While we use commercially reasonable efforts to protect your personal information from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure, we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information. In the event that we are required by law to inform you of a breach to your personal information we may notify you electronically, in writing, or by telephone, if permitted to do so by law.

Some of our websites permit you to create a Barnes & Noble account. When you do you will be prompted to create a password. You are responsible for maintaining the confidentiality of your password, and you are responsible for any access to or use of your account by someone else that has obtained your password, whether or not such access or use has been authorized by you. You should notify us of any unauthorized use of your password or account. For more information, please visit the Barnes & Noble [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/about/terms-of-use).

HOW DO WE HANDLE CHILDREN’S DATA?
---------------------------------

### Policies for Minors, including children under the age of 16

Barnes & Noble is committed to complying with all applicable laws and regulations regarding the collection, storage and use of personal information of Minors under the age of 16, including the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998.

Except as noted below: (i) our products and services are marketed for and directed towards purchase by adults or with the consent of adults; (ii) Individuals under the age of 18 (“Minors”) are not permitted to use Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps without the supervision of a parent or legal guardian; (iii) we do not knowingly collect or solicit personal information from children under the age of 16 or knowingly allow such persons to register for an online account or to post personal information on the Barnes & Noble Websites; and (v) should we learn that someone under the age of 16 has provided any personal information to or on any of the Barnes & Noble Websites, we will remove that information as soon as possible.

We do not knowingly sell or share personal information about consumers under the age of 16.

If we direct certain Devices features or Apps to Minors who may be under the age of 16, we require the parent or legal guardian to provide verifiable consent to such Minor’s use of our products and services and our collection of personal information in connection with such use. In these cases, we require validation of credit card information already on file with us and we will then email the master account holder to give notice that we have received such consent. If no credit card information is on file, or if the credit card is invalid, we will not register that you have consented. With your consent, we may collect, use and share information regarding Minors under the age of 16 consistent with this Privacy Policy. Please see the sections above for detailed information on how we do so.

If you are a parent or guardian who believes that your Minor under the age of 16 has submitted personal information or other information to us without your consent, please contact [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com). Once we verify that you are the parent or legal guardian, at your request, we will promptly provide to you information regarding what, if any, personal information we have collected about your child and how it has been used or shared. We will, at your request, remove personal information about your child from its database and instruct our affiliates to do the same.

If you are a Minor under the age of 18, you may request and obtain removal of certain content or information posted on Barnes & Noble Websites and Apps by sending an email to [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) with “Privacy Rights for Minors” in the subject line. Please be advised that our removal of your post(s) does not ensure complete or comprehensive removal of the content or information you have posted on Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps.

HOW DO WE RESPECT YOUR CHOICES ABOUT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?
---------------------------------------------------------------

You may choose to opt out from receiving marketing and promotional communications from Barnes & Noble at any time by following the instructions below.

* **For Barnes & Noble Booksellers:** At any time, a customer may choose to opt-out of the receipt of any promotional communications by clicking on the opt-out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions, or by emailing our Customer Service Department by [clicking here](https://help.barnesandnoble.com/hc/en-us).
* **For Barnes & Noble account Holders:** Any account holder can opt-out of the receipt of any promotional communications by logging onto their Account and following the instructions under “Communication Preferences”. If you do not have a Barnes & Noble account, you may opt out of the receipt of such communications by selecting the link at the bottom of any promotional email communication and following the instructions.
* **For Barnes & Noble or Paper Source Member programs:** Any participant can opt out of the receipt of any Member program promotional communications by logging on to their Barnes & Noble account and following the instructions under “Change Your Communication Preferences.” If you do not have a Barnes & Noble account, you may opt-out of the receipt of such communications by selecting the link at the bottom of any promotional email communication and following the instructions.
* **For the Barnes & Noble Gift Card website:** Any customer of the Barnes & Noble Gift Card website who receives promotional communications can opt-out of the receipt of any such communications by clicking on the opt-out link provided at the bottom of each email and following the instructions or by sending an email to giftcardorders@bn.com. Even if you opt-out of receiving promotional communications, you may continue to receive emails and notifications relating to order confirmations, back-order notifications, membership information, and/or other business-related communications.

BARNES & NOBLE DOES NOT SELL OR SHARE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION.
----------------------------------------------------------------

We do not provide your name, phone number, address, email address or other personally identifiable information to third parties in exchange for money.

However, under certain state privacy laws, sharing information for advertising purposes may be considered a “sale” or “sharing” of “personal information.” “Sale,” broadly means scenarios in which we have disclosed personal information with partners in exchange for valuable consideration. “Sharing” means that we make available or otherwise disclose your information to third parties for cross-contextual behavioral advertising, such as targeting advertising to you, based on your personal information obtained from your activity across businesses, websites, apps, and services other than our Services.

We may share your IP Address information for targeted advertising if you visit the SparkNotes website.

You have the right to opt out of the “sale” or “sharing” of personal information, and we’ve made it possible for you to stop the information transfers that might be considered such a “sale” from our website or applications by visiting the following link: [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://bn.clarip.com/dsr/create?type=3). We will not discriminate against you for exercising your privacy rights.

### Analytics

You may choose to opt out of collection of automatically collected information, including cookies, Adobe Analytics, Google Analytics, and Localytics, by following the instructions given in the section entitled **Information Automatically Collected** above, or by using the functionality in your browser to reject cookies.

### Targeted Advertising

You may choose to opt out of targeted advertising, by following the instructions given in section entitled **Information Automatically Collected** above, or by using the functionality in your browser to reject cookies. You may also opt out of the sharing of your personal information for targeted advertising purposes by visiting the following link: [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://bn.clarip.com/dsr/create?type=3) or by visiting our Services with a legally-recognized opt-out preference signal enabled (such as the Global Privacy Control).

### Online Community Users

Barnes & Noble provides you with the ability to access, correct, change or request deletion of the personal information in your community profile(s) at any time by following the instructions below. However, you cannot currently change your profile name although you may re-register and choose a new name. To review or modify your profile information, please click here. Please be advised that Barnes & Noble may archive information it collects on its community and visitors. Additionally, by participating in the Barnes & Noble online interactive community, including but not limited to, the submission of customer reviews, participation in Barnes & Noble’s other various interactive offerings, you agree to receive communications from Barnes & Noble, other users, and moderators related to the provision of these services.

HOW DO I EXERCISE MY PRIVACY RIGHTS AND CHOICES?
------------------------------------------------

You have the right to ask us not to use your personal information for direct marketing purposes. You have the right to request a copy of the personal information that we hold about you and to have any inaccuracies rectified. You have the right to request that we delete your personal information. If required by law we will grant a request to delete information, but you should note that in many situations we must keep your personal information to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, enforce our agreements, or for another one of our business purposes.

Please address written requests and questions about your rights to [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) or call us at 1-800-THE-BOOK **\[1-800-843-2665\]**. You may submit a request for a copy of the personal information that we hold about you through our [online portal](https://bn.clarip.com/dsr/create?type=3).

Note that, as required by law, we will require you to prove your identity. We may conduct an identity verification by phone call or email. Depending on your request, we will ask for information such as your name, the last item you purchased from us, or the date of your last purchase from us. We may also ask you to provide a signed declaration confirming your identity. Following a request, we will use reasonable efforts to supply, correct or delete personal information about you in our files.

If we deny your request, you may appeal our decision by contacting us at [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com). Please include all prior communications with us concerning your request. If you have concerns about the results of an appeal, you may contact the attorney general in the state where you reside.

### Authorized Agent policy

You may use an authorized agent to submit a request to access your information, delete your information, or opt out of the sale of your information. To designate an agent for these purposes:

1. You must provide us with a copy of a written and signed permission given to your authorized agent; and
2. You must verify your own identity directly with us.

ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES: U.S. STATE PRIVACY NOTICE & CALIFORNIA NOTICE AT COLLECTION
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Many states in the United States have passed or are in the processes of passing comprehensive consumer privacy laws. One such law is the California Consumer Privacy Act, as amended by the California Consumer Privacy Rights Act (“CCPA”). These consumer privacy laws grant their residents certain rights and require additional disclosures (“State Privacy Laws”). If you are a resident of one of a state that has enacted State Privacy Laws, this section applies to you.

### Personal Information Collected and Shared

Certain State Privacy Laws, including the CCPA, require us to disclose what categories of information we have collected in the last twelve months and what categories of information we have “shared” or “sold” as those terms are defined under California law. You can find a list of the categories of information that we have collected and shared or sold, as those terms are defined under applicable State Privacy Laws [here](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/california-information-sharing-disclosure). Please note that because these lists are comprehensive, they may refer to types of information that we share about people other than yourself. If you would like more information concerning the categories of personal information (if any) we share with third parties or affiliates for those parties to use for direct marketing please submit a written request to us using the information in the “Contact Information” section below. We do not discriminate against consumers who exercise any of their rights described in this policy.

You can find additional information regarding the number of requests Barnes & Noble received and responded to under the CCPA [here](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/ccpa-requests).

### Shine the Light

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. Under the law, a business must either provide this information or permit California residents to opt in to, or opt out of, this type of sharing. We qualify for this alternative option. To opt out of having information about you shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes, please visit the following link: [Do Not Sell My Personal Information](https://bn.clarip.com/dsr/create?type=3).

### Important information about third party devices, ISPs, websites and applications

This Privacy Policy applies solely to information collected by the Barnes & Noble enterprise. Whenever you click on links and banners on any Barnes & Noble Website that take you to a third-party website or you use, download or install third party software applications onto your Device, your use of those third party websites and/or software will be subject to the third party’s privacy policies, not Barnes & Noble’s. Additionally, please note that when using Barnes & Noble Websites or Apps, third party mobile device manufacturers and internet service providers (ISPs) may collect personal information about you and your use of such third-party products and services will be subject to the third party’s privacy policies.

In addition, our website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Barnes & Noble. If you submit personal information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy policies. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy policy of any website you visit.

### Notice of Financial Incentive and Bona Fide Loyalty Programs

We provide price discounts, coupons, services, and other benefits for (1) members of our Barnes & Noble Premium Membership Program, Barnes & Noble Rewards, Em & Friends — Friends with Benefits, Paper Source Marketing Program, Cafe and other customer programs; (2) large volume customers; (3) members of our mailing list; and (4) Barnes & Noble Account Holders (collectively “Programs”).

Through these offerings, customers provide us with the necessary personal information (e.g., names, emails, phone numbers, etc.) when they opt-in to our programs. There is no obligation to opt-in and customers may opt-out at any time. The details of each Program are contained in the terms and conditions for each Program. We offer these Programs, among other things, to enhance our relationship with you so you can enjoy more of our products/services at a lower price. We invest heavily in our marketing and brands, in part, so we can provide Programs to our customers. The value to our business of customers’ personal information is dependent on specific facts such as whether and to what extent they, in the aggregate, take advantage of any offerings and whether and to what extent they opt-out of any offerings. Our ability to create any value from the Programs is heavily based on our ability to leverage said intellectual properties. We do not calculate the value of customer data in our accounting statements. To the extent we create overall value from our Programs to our business that could be directly or reasonably related to the value of customer data in the aggregate, the method for calculating same would include: the costs associated with (1) our intellectual property; (2) enhancing customer data by our marketing team’s efforts; (3) leveraging our significant investments in understanding you as our existing and future customers; (4) all other costs reasonably related to the programs and (5) for each program, and in the aggregate, whether the sales generated by the program(s) exceed the cost to us of offering them. We estimate that the value of these Programs is at least equal to the value of the information you provide when you participate in them.

You can opt-in to, or opt-out of, our Programs at any time through the same means they are offered, or by emailing our Customer Service Department by calling Customer Service at 1-800-THE-BOOK **\[1-800-843-2665\]**.

To see what personal information we have collected or shared in the last twelve months, [click here](https://www.barnesandnoble.com/h/help/collection-sharing-selling-disclosure).

ADDITIONAL DISCLOSURES FOR VISITORS OUTSIDE THE U.S., INCLUDING IN THE EU, UK & SWITZERLAND, AND INFORMATION ON INTERNATIONAL DATA TRANSFERS
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

Barnes & Noble is headquartered in the United States. By doing business or interacting with Barnes & Noble, you are consenting to the transfer, storage, and processing of your personal information to and within facilities located in the United States and other facility locations selected by Barnes & Noble. We will take steps to ensure that your personal information receives an adequate level of protection in the jurisdictions in which we process it. Any international transfers of personal information will be in accordance with this Privacy Policy and in compliance with applicable laws.

### Disclosures for Individuals in EU, UK & Switzerland

If you are located in the EU, UK, or Switzerland, you have certain rights and protections under the law regarding the processing of your personal data.

When we process your personal information or data, we will do so in reliance on one or more of the following lawful bases:

* To perform our responsibilities under our contract with you (e.g., processing payments for and providing the products and services you requested).
* When we have a legitimate interest in processing your personal data to operate our business or protect our interests (e.g., to provide, maintain, and improve our products and services and to communicate with you).
* To comply with our legal obligations (e.g., to maintain a record of your consents, track those who have opted out of marketing communications, and comply with other regulatory obligations).
* When we have your consent to do so (e.g., when you opt in to receive marketing communications from us). When consent is the legal basis for our processing your personal data, you may withdraw such consent at any time.

Subject to certain limitations, you have the following rights:

* The right to request access to the personal information or data we hold about you and to receive your data in a portable format.
* The right to ask that your personal information or data be corrected.
* The right to ask that your personal information or data be deleted or erased.
* The right to object to, or request that we restrict, certain processing.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please see **How Do I Exercise My Privacy Rights and Choices?** above for contact information, portal access, and for additional information on our verification process.

### Supervisory Authorities

If you have a concern about our processing of personal data that we are not able to resolve, you have the right to lodge a complaint with the Data Protection Authority where you reside. Contact details for your Data Protection Authority can be found using the links below:

For individuals in the EEA: [https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members\_en](https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members_en)

For individuals in the UK: [https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/](https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/)

For individuals in Switzerland: [https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/contact.html](https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/the-fdpic/contact.html)

### The Data Privacy Framework

Barnes & Noble participates in the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (“EU-U.S. DPF”), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (collectively, “Data Privacy Framework” or “DPF”) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce and approved by the European Commission, UK Information Commissioner’s Office, and the Swiss Data Federal Data Protection Commission. The Barnes & Noble subsidiaries that participate in the DPF include the following:

* Barnes & Noble Booksellers, Inc.,
* Barnes & Noble Purchasing, Inc.,
* Barnes & Noble Services, Inc.,
* Sterling Publishing Co., Inc.,
* Union Square & Co., LLC
* Knock Knock LLC,
* Pondview Books LLC,
* Barnes & Noble Café, LLC,
* Barnes & Noble Café Texas Holdings, LLC,
* Barnes & Noble Café Texas, LLC,
* Barnes & Noble Marketing Services, LLC,
* Nook Digital, LLC,
* SparkNotes LLC,
* Papershop Topco LLC,
* Papershop Finco LLC,
* Paper Source LLC, and
* Paper Source Marketing Services, LLC.

Barnes & Noble and the subsidiaries listed above commit to comply with the DPF’s Data Privacy Framework Principles (“DPF Principles”) with regard to the processing of personal information received from the European Union, the United Kingdom, and Switzerland in reliance on the DPF.

If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the DPF Principles, the DPF Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (DPF) program, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/). To view our certification, please visit [https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/list](https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/list).

If third-party agents process personal data on our behalf in a manner inconsistent with the DPF Principles, we remain liable unless we prove we are not responsible for the event giving rise to any damages. If you have a question or complaint related to our compliance with the DPF Principles, please first contact Barnes & Noble at: [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com)

We commit to refer unresolved complaints concerning our handling of personal data received in reliance on the DPF to JAMS, an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your DPF Principles-related complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your DPF Principles-related complaint to your satisfaction, please visit [https://www.jamsadr.com/DPF-Dispute-Resolution](https://www.jamsadr.com/DPF-Dispute-Resolution) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of JAMS are provided at no cost to you. JAMS mediation may be commenced as provided for in the JAMS rules. Following the dispute resolution process, the mediator or the consumer may refer the matter to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, which has Data Privacy Framework investigatory and enforcement powers over Barnes & Noble. Under limited circumstances, and after other available dispute resolution mechanisms have been exhausted, consumers may be able to invoke binding arbitration to address complaints about our compliance with the DPF Principles.

### Disclosures for Other Visitors Outside the U.S.

Some jurisdictions outside the United States have provided individuals with certain rights in relation to the processing of their personal information. If you would like to exercise any of these rights, please see How Do I Exercise My Privacy Rights and Choices? above for contact information, portal access, and for additional information on our verification process.

**By doing business or interacting with Barnes & Noble, you are consenting to the transfer, storage, and processing of your personal information to and within facilities located in the United States and other facility locations selected by Barnes & Noble.** If you are concerned about how your personal information is used, please email us at [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) or contact us.

HOW LONG DOES BARNES & NOBLE KEEP MY PERSONAL DATA?
---------------------------------------------------

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. Otherwise, personal information associated with expired or deactivated accounts will be deleted within two (2) years of inactivity or deactivation.

WHOM DO I CONTACT AT BARNES & NOBLE IF I HAVE QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS?
--------------------------------------------------------------------

If you have questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, you may contact us by emailing [privacy@barnesandnoble.com](mailto:privacy@barnesandnoble.com) or call customer service at 1-800-THE-BOOK **\[1-800-843-2665\]**. You may also mail inquiries and concerns to: Chief Privacy Officer, Barnes & Noble Inc., 33 East 17th Street, New York, NY 10003.

**Effective Date: March 22, 2024**
